ebooks.com 2018-12-27

# eBooks.com: Privacy Policy

### Last Updated: May 25, 2018

This privacy policy applies to www.ebooks.com owned and operated by Ebooks.com Pty Limited. This privacy policy describes how Ebooks.com Pty Limited collects and uses the personally identifiable information you provide on our web site: www.ebooks.com. It also describes the choices available to you regarding our use of your personally identifiable information and how you can access and update this information.

eBooks.com respects your privacy. As we develop our online presence, we will revise our Privacy Policy to reflect our practices and to meet any legislative or other requirements. The terms of this Privacy Policy form part of and should be read in conjunction with the Terms of Use and Licenses which govern this Website.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>

#### Collection of personally identifiable information

Ebooks.com Pty Limited is the sole owner of the information collected on eBooks.com. eBooks.com collects personally identifiable information from our users at several different points on our Web site. 

If you purchase a product or service from us, we request certain personally identifiable information from you on our order form. You must provide contact information (such as name, email, and billing address) and financial information (such as credit card number, expiration date). 

We use this information for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we will use this information to contact you. 

After registering an account with us, you will receive an email containing a welcome message and your login details. After successfully completing a purchase, you will receive an email receipt of your order. 

If you purchase a gift certificate from us, we will ask you for the name and email address of the recipient in order to fulfill the purchase request. The information is not used for any other purpose. 

eBooks.com will collect information generated by its webservers for the purpose of assessing the technical performance of its systems and to enhance service levels. 

From time to time, we may also request and you may choose to provide us with personally identifiable information through the use of the Website or through email addresses available from our Website. 

If you do not provide us with the personally identifiable information that we request, we may not be able to properly assess your request for service and the level of service we can provide you may be reduced to the extent that you do not provide us with relevant information. 

We will not collect sensitive information about you from anyone else without your consent.

#### Use and Disclosure of Information 

We will use personally identifiable information you provide to us for the purpose of providing you with the service or product that you have requested. We do not share personally identifiable information with third parties. 

We will not sell, rent, trade, share, reveal or disclose any of your personally identifiable information, unless 

  * you have specifically requested that we do so;
  * we deem it necessary to provide you with services you have requested;
  * required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities 
  * as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, bankruptcy proceedings, or similar legal process;
  * our terms and conditions state that we will;
  * when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; or
  * We have reason to suspect that unlawful activity has been, is being or may be engaged in and the use or disclosure of your personally identifiable information is a necessary part of our investigation of the matter or in reporting our concerns to relevant persons or authorities. 

We may provide aggregate information and statistics about eBooks.com's customers, sales traffic patterns and related site information to third parties but these statistics will not include individual personally identifiable information. We use a credit card processing company to bill you for goods and services. These companies do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any other purposes. 

We may provide your personal information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order or offering customer service. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us. 

We may use your contact information to send you information about our Services, to market to you, and to help prevent spam, fraud or abuse. You may use your settings for email and mobile notifications to control notifications you receive from us. You may also unsubscribe from a notification by following the instructions contained within the notification or the instructions on our website. 

#### Tracking Technologies

We Ebooks.com Pty Limited and our affiliates, or analytics use technologies such as cookies, beacons, tags, and scripts, to analyze trends, administer the website, tracking users' movements around the website, and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual and aggregated basis. 

We use cookies to improve the functionality of it's site and to support all browsers. eBooks.com uses cookies to assess the performance of the Website and to confirm your preferences and for user authentication. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our website, but your ability to use some features or areas of our website may be limited. 

We use Local Storage, such as HTML5, to store content information and preferences. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5. 

We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our website or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this website and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](https://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads. 

#### Analytics/Log files

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and clickstream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.

We do not link this automatically-collected data to personally identifiable information. 

#### Access to Personally Identifiable Information

Upon request Ebooks.com Pty Limited will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update, delete/remove it by logging in to your account or by emailng Customer Support at privacy@ebooks.com or by contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. 

We will retain your information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. 

#### Choice/Opt Out

We provide you the opportunity to "opt-out" of having your personally identifiable information used for certain purposes, when we ask for this information. For example, if you create an account but do not wish to receive any additional marketing/promotional material from us, you can indicate your preference on our registration form. Customers may not opt-out of purchase receipts and confirmation emails as these are obligatory. 

If you sign up for our email alerts, notifying you of new book releases, and you no longer wish to receive our alerts and promotional communications, you may opt-out of receiving them by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication or by emailing us at privacy@ebooks.com. 

You will be notified when your personally identifiable information is collected by any third party that is not our agent/service provider, so you can make an informed choice as to whether or not to share your information with that party. 

#### Data Security

eBooks.com takes your privacy and the privacy of all its customers very seriously. We follow generally accepted standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once it is received. 

If you have any concerns about your privacy and the use of the Website or any of eBooks.com's services or products, please contact privacy@ebooks.com. We will respond to your request to access 30 days. 

You may request that we provide you with a copy of the personally identifiable information collected by us from your use of the Website or through your dealings with us. You may make this request by contact us through our Online Support Form and providing the requested details. 

#### E-commerce Policy

If you choose to purchase a product or service from eBooks.com online, eBooks.com only stores enough information concerning your transaction as to permit it to verify your instructions and reconcile payment information from its merchant clearance system. 

Authorize.Net Corporation   
3311 N. University Avenue   
Provo, UT 84604-4445 USA 

WorldPay Limited  
Units 270 -289  
The Science Park  
Milton Road  
Cambridge  
CB4 0WE  
United Kingdon  

By default, credit card details are encrypted and stored for use with future purchases. Internally, eBooks.com takes extra caution to limit access to customers' information. Only a few individuals within the company are given degrees of access to customers' personally identifiable information according to job function and necessity. Access is granted to these employees through special passwords. All employees are kept up to date on our security and privacy practices. Finally, the servers that store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure, guarded environment. If you would like your details removed, please submit a request through our support form. 

#### Tell-a-Friend

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. Ebooks.com does not store this information. 

#### eBooks.com acts as agent

In addition to operating as an online retailer of ebooks in its own right, eBooks.com also provides sales, fulfillment, payment processing and help-desk services to other companies on an agency basis. This service is most commonly provided to book publishers. We will make it clear to you whenever we are so acting as an agent, by showing the brand of the other company at the top of our web pages. The other company's brand will be followed by the words "Powered by eBooks.com" or similar. When we sell you an ebook in our capacity as agent, the vendor of record for that purchase will be the other company. When so acting as an agent, we may provide to the other company your personally identifiable information, so that they may continue to service your needs in the event that the partnership between eBooks.com and the other company ceases. If you opt-in to receive marketing information we may pass your information onto our partners, whom we act as agents, so they may continue that service. If you do not want us to share your personally identifiable information with these companies, contact us at privacy@ebooks.com 

#### Links to Other Sites

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by eBooks.com. Please be aware that we, eBooks.com, are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. 

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policy of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. 

This privacy statement applies only to information collected by this Web site.

#### Social Media Widgets

Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook Like button and Widgets, such as Twitter and Blogspot or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

#### Changes to Privacy Policy

We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this policy, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our home page prior to the change becoming effective. 

#### Business Transitions

In the event that eBooks.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via a notice on our Web site for 30 days of any such change in ownership or control of your personally identifiable information. 

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions or suggestions regarding our privacy policy, please contact us at:

EBOOKS.COM Pty Limited, trading as eBooks.com  
27 Railway Rd,  
Subiaco, WA 6008  
Australia  
Ph: (08) 9385 5851  
privacy@ebooks.com

ABN: 14 146 279 370 

### GDPR Addendum 25th May 2018

The following clauses supplement eBooks.com’s privacy policy (above), in compliance with the European GDPR regulations which came into effect on 25th May 2018. For the avoidance of doubt, in the event that any provision in this GDPR Addendum conflicts with our privacy policy above, such provision of the GDPR Addendum will prevail.

#### eBooks.com’s Business

We conduct the following business:

  1. Provide intelligent, helpful reading recommendations to our members.
  2. Enable our members, through the eBooks.com website and its associated domains and apps (collectively the “Website”), to buy, borrow or otherwise acquire access to, download, store, read, use and manage ebooks for their personal use.

#### The domains and services covered by this privacy policy

  1. ebooks.com
  2. eb20.com
  3. Ebook Reader mobile app

#### Reasons/purposes for processing information

We process personal information to enable us to make better, more helpful reading recommendations; to sell goods and services to and to support and advise our members; to promote and advertise our services; maintain our own accounts and records and to support and manage our employees.

In order to perform these tasks well, we need to store information about you and your correspondence with us, and your shopping and browsing activity on the Website.

There are only two lawful reasons that we process and store information about you, and they have formal, legal definitions which you can find [here](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/lawful-basis-for-processing/):

  1. **Consent** : You have given clear consent for us to process your personal data for a specific purpose.
  2. **Legitimate Interests** : The processing is necessary, in order for us to provide the products and services that we offer, or to enable you to benefit most from eBooks.com.

#### The kind of information eBooks.com collects

#### Data that we might store when you visit our website, before you sign up as a member of eBooks.com

**Information**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Lawful basis**  
  
---|---|---  
  
**IP address**

We detect and store your IP address [[definition](https://www.techopedia.com/definition/2435/internet-protocol-address-ip-address)] whenever you visit eBooks.com

| 

Geo-Location customisation

| 

**Legitimate interests.**

 If we know your IP address, we can customise your experience on eBooks.com so that we will display content to you that is relevant to your location. For example, we’ll show you bestseller lists, and offer you topical new titles that are relevant to your location.

Additionally, we are required under many of our supply agreements to take note of visitors’ IP addresses in order to keep promises we’ve made to book publishers that we will restrict the sale of their ebooks so that they are only offered for sale in those territories for which each publisher has permission to sell those ebooks.  
  
**Cookie Information**

Referring URL

Unique identifier

| 

Sales referral attribution

Shopping cart contents

Customised recommendations

| 

**Legitimate interests**

Cookies enable us to keep track of what you've put in your shopping cart and remember who you are when you return to our site.

Cookies enable us to meet our contractual obligations to make payments to third parties (like Google and Commission Junction) when a product is purchased by someone who was referred to our website from a site operated by those parties.  
  
#### Further data that we might store after you’ve signed up.

**Information**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Lawful basis**  
  
---|---|---  
  
**Titles of the ebooks that you have bought or shown an interest in, including:**

Titles you have bought from us

Titles you have clicked on

Words or phrases you’ve searched for

Titles you add to your wish list

Titles you’ve added to the shopping cart but have not yet bought

Subject categories of ebooks you’ve bought or shown an interest in

| 

This enables us to keep a proper record of your ebooks, so they will always be accessible to you after you’ve bought them.

We keep your wish-list up to date on your behalf.

And the information helps us to make useful reading suggestions.

| 

**Legitimate interests**

We act as custodians of the ebooks you’ve bought from us and accordingly we maintain your “eBookshelf” and wish list for your future access and use.

In our role as a recommendation service, we use this information to provide you with useful advice about what to read.

If you put an ebook in your shopping cart and then don’t buy it, we might remind you about that next time you visit, or notify you within our apps or via email.  
  
**Personal details, including:**

your name,

address,

phone number,

email address,

website login password,

credit card numbers, expiry dates and CVV codes,

the history of your financial transactions with us, and

any correspondence you conduct with us.

| 

This information is collected to enable us to protect the security of your eBooks.com account and your credit cards, to quickly process your card payments, and in order to conduct normal day-to-day business with you.

| 

**Legitimate interests**.

It is necessary for us to collect and hold this information to make your experience at eBooks.com simple and efficient, and for us to be able to contact you as our customer in the normal course of business.

Email recommendations  
  
**For each browser session when you log in to your account at eBooks.com, we store the following information:**

Your IP address

Browser type (Chrome, Firefox, etc.)

Browser Version number

Color Depth (a number that describes how colours are displayed on the screen)

CPU (the central processing unit in your computer or device. Sometimes called the “brains” of the computer.)

Date and time of your visit

Device name (E,g., “iPad”)

Device Type (Whether your device is a computer, tablet or phone)

Flash Version

Installed Fonts

JavaVersion

MimeTypes

OS

OsVersoin

Installed Browser Plugins

Screen resolution of your device (dimensions)

SilverLightVersion

System Language

Time zone

User Agent

Date and time of any ebook downloads

| 

To customise your experience at eBooks.com

| 

**Legitimate interests.**

By understanding the hardware and software in your computer or device and your location, we are able to **customise your experience** on eBooks.com so that we display content to you that is relevant to your location, and our system will configure our web pages so that they look and function better for you.

For example, we’ll show you bestseller lists, and offer you topical new titles that are relevant to your location. And knowing the type and dimensions of your device enables us to display our content in a more pleasing way.

We are obliged under our supply agreements with book publishers to take note of visitors’ geographic location in order to keep promises we’ve made to book publishers that we will restrict the sale of their ebooks so that they are only offered for sale in those territories for which each publisher has permission to sell those ebooks.

We are obliged under our supply agreements with book publishers to impose limits on the frequency with which users download a given ebook. Tracking the date and time of your ebook downloads enables us to comply with these obligations.  
  
**Each time you access an ebook using our**[ **online reader**](http://about.ebooks.com/ebooks-coms-online-ebook-reader-app/) **app. (That’s a web browser-based reading application. This is different from when you download a whole ebook to your computer or device.)**

The information below is collected in addition to the information we collect whenever you access our Website:

Your reading progress through the ebook

Any “annotations” you make; including notes, highlighting and book-marks.

Length of time each reading session takes.

| 

Enables the proper functioning of the Online Reader

| 

**Legitimate interests.**

It is necessary for us to retain this information, so that:

you will be able to resume at the last page you were reading, next time you open to the ebook, and

You’ll be able to keep your margin notes, book-marks and any highlighting you’ve made within the pages of the ebook.  
  
**Your correspondence with us:**

Email messages you send to eBooks.com,

Messages you post on our Website such as support queries, comments and product reviews.

| 

So we can respond helpfully the next time you contact us

| 

**Legitimate interests**

It is necessary for us to retain this correspondence, as is common practice in all well-run businesses.  
  
#### Sharing your information with third parties

We use your information only as set out in this Policy and will not sell, rent or pass your information on to others for marketing purposes without your consent.

We may however provide aggregate statistics about our customers, sales traffic patterns and related site information to reputable third-party vendors and relevant affiliate partners, but these statistics will include no personally identifying information.

We never pass on information to any third party which would enable the recipient to identify you personally, except:

  1. For the purpose of processing purchase transactions (credit card, PayPal, etc.), and
  2. Where we believe in good faith that this release is reasonably necessary to comply with the law.

We may provide information to the following service providers for the reasons set out below. 

**Third Party**

| 

**Information**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Lawful basis**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
**Payment processing services including PayPal and Stripe**

| 

Personal details, including your name, address, phone number, email address, credit card numbers, expiry dates and CVV codes, and your IP address

| 

Payment processing

| 

**Legitimate interests**.  
  
#### Where your data is stored

eBooks.com partners with Cogeco Peer1 for the supply of Data Centre services.  
<https://www.cogecopeer1.com/>

Cogeco Peer1,  
145 King Street West, 8th floor  
Toronto, ON  
M5H 1J8

#### Cookies

Our site uses cookies to keep track of your visits to our website. A cookie is a small file that can be stored by your browser on your computer's hard drive. We may use these to do a number of things:

  * We use cookies to deliver content specific to your interest and to save your password so that you don't have to re-enter it every time you visit our site.
  * Cookies help us to recognise when you next visit our website and note the recommendations displayed to you. This allows us to tailor the service we provide to your preferences.

You can usually change your browser so that it will not accept cookies. If you'd like to learn more about cookies in general and how to manage them, visit [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)

#### What Are Cookies?

eBooks.com places tiny text files called cookies onto your computer, tablet or mobile device. This is standard practice for almost all websites.

Cookies are not harmful to your computer and are an essential part of online shopping. They allow us to give you a more efficient customer experience.

#### What Are Cookies Used For?

There are two main types of cookie; we call them "first party" and "third party" cookies.

First party cookies are small data files that we use for things such as keeping track of what you've put in your basket and remembering who you are when you return to our site. We don't save personal information such as credit card details in the cookies we create.

Third party cookies are set on our behalf. The most important of these are Google and Commission Junction, who display text or banner adverts on our behalf on a number of other reputable websites or in Internet search results. Commission Junction does not collect personal data from our website. Because our website uses Google Analytics to help us optimise our web pages and better understand the website’s traffic, if you visit us while you’re logged in to your Google account (like Gmail, for example) then some of your browsing activity on our site may be …

<https://www.google.com/policies/technologies/partner-sites/>

Cookies enable us to meet our contractual obligations to make payments to third parties (like Google and Commission Junction) when a product is purchased by someone who has visited our website from a site operated by those parties.

#### Email and In-App Marketing

We send three types of timely messages to our members:

**Message type**

| 

**Consent-type**

| 

**Purpose**

| 

**Lawful basis**  
  
---|---|---|---  
  
**Subject category recommendation newsletters**

| 

Opt-in

| 

Members can sign up to receive occasional, curated reading suggestions from our editors.  
You can control which newsletters you receive, if any, here.

| 

**Consent**

You will only be enrolled in our newsletter service if you choose to do so.  
  
**Critical system, policy or service announcements**

| 

You can’t opt out of these necessary, critical messages, except by closing your account with eBooks.com.

| 

We, very rarely, need to contact our members to advise them of changes to our services or policies, or system updates.

| 

**Legitimate interests**

As with any business relationship it is sometimes necessary for us to contact you.  
  
**Reminders and _ad hoc_ alerts.**

| 

Opt-out

| 

In our role as a recommendation service we will occasionally contact you with reading recommendations (like a new ebook from an author you’ve read before); or we might remind you that you left an ebook in your shopping cart – that kind of thing.

You can opt out of these messages here.

| 

**Legitimate interests**

We send reminders and ad hoc alerts to our members as part of our recommendation service.  
  
#### How can I access the personal information that eBooks.com holds?

Contact our support team and they’ll be glad to help.

#### Can I withdraw consent and request the deletion of my information?

Yes – just contact our support team and they’ll be glad to help.
